<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./registry.xsl"?>
<registry xmlns="urn:nena:xml:namespace:nrs" id="elementState" registrar="nena" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:nena:xml:namespace:nrs registry.xsd">
	<title>RouteCause</title>
	<created>2011-06-14</created>
	<updated>2011-06-14</updated>
    <registry ref="../../nrs">NRS</registry>
    <references>
        <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
    </references>
	<registration_rule>Expert Review Required</registration_rule>
	<description>The ESRP routes calls using its Policy Routing Function.  The result of evaluating a ruleset is a Route action which routes the call towards a PSAP (or responder).  The Route action includes a cause value, which is placed in a Reason header associated with a History-Info header that informs the recipient why it got the call.  A registry is needed for the values in the cause.  The Route action cause is an enumeration, but the Reason header has a numeric cause value and a text string.</description>
	<note>A new entry to RouteCause requires an explanation of the use of the new cause and how it is differentiated from other values in the registry.  There is little reason to constrain the number of entries in the Registry as long as the value definitions are distinct enough for recipients to understand why the call was received.  The Expert should therefore grant new requests for values as long as the value is clearly differentiateable from existing values.  There should not be proprietary values, i.e. values that are expressly created for a particular implementation and generally not intended to be used by other implementations.  Rather the values should have wide applicability to any implementation.</note>
	<records>
      <record>
        <value>NormalNextHop</value>
        <code>200</code>
        <text>Normal Next Hop</text>
        <references>
            <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
        </references>
        <date>2011-06-14</date>
      </record>
      <record>
        <value>TimeOfDay</value>
        <code>401</code>
        <text>Time of Day</text>
        <references>
            <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
        </references>
        <date>2011-06-14</date>
      </record>
      <record>
        <value></value>
        <code>402</code>
        <text></text>
        <references>
            <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
        </references>
        <date>2011-06-14</date>
      </record>
	</records>
</registry>
