<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./registry.xsl"?>
<registry xmlns="urn:nena:xml:namespace:nrs" id="elementState" registrar="nena" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:nena:xml:namespace:nrs registry.xsd">
	<title>LogEvent</title>
	<created>2011-06-14</created>
	<updated>2011-06-14</updated>
    <registry ref="../../nrs">NRS</registry>
    <references>
        <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
    </references>
	<registration_rule>NENA Technical Standard Required</registration_rule>
	<description>Log entries have a LogEvent which specifies what kind of log record the entry contains.</description>
	<note>A new entry to LogEvent requires an explanation of the new value, when it would be used, and the parameters required in the log record.</note>
	<records>
		<record>
			<value>CallProcess</value>
			<description>Each element which is not call stateful, but handles a call logs the fact that it saw the call pass through by logging a CallProcess event.  There are no parameters to “Call Process”.</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>StartCall</value>
			<description>Each element which is call stateful logs the beginning of its processing of a call with StartCall events.  StartCall includes a copy of the headers in the INVITE message, encoded in &lt;header&gt; tags.</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>EndCall</value>
			<description>Each element which is call stateful logs the end of its processing of a call with EndCall events.  EndCall includes the response code that ended the call (200 OK in the case of a successful call), encoded in a &lt;responseCode&gt; tag.</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>TransferCall</value>
			<description>When a call is transferred, the transfer is logged by the transferor (the PSAP which had the call prior to transferring it. The transfer target URI is logged in a &lt;transferTarget&gt; tag.</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>Route</value>
			<description>Proxy servers that make routing decisions (ESRPs or othe SIP proxy servers in the path of the call) log the route it selected with the Route EventType.  The URI where it decided to send the call (encoded in a &lt;uri&gt; tag, plus a text string &lt;reason&gt; for choosing that route are included in the LogEvent.  For ESRPs, the name of the rule is included in a &lt;rule&gt; tag.</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>Media</value>
			<description>Media is the log of call media (voice, video and interactive text).  The media event includes a text string &lt;udp&gt; tag that contains an RFC2327 Session Description Protocol [55] description of the media.  The SDP must include SDES keys if the RTP stream is protected with SRTP.  Each independent stream must include an RFC4574 [138] label to identify each stream and the label must be logged with a &lt;mediaLabel&gt; tag.  More than one Media event can occur for a call.  Recorded media streams include integral time reference data within the stream.</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>EndMedia</value>
			<description>EndMedia causes the logging service to terminate recording of media.  The EndMedia event includes one or more &lt;mediaLabel&gt; tags which must match the SDP labels in the corresponding Media event.  More than one EndMedia (with different &lt;mediaLabel&gt;s) may occur for a call.</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>Message</value>
			<description>An SIP Message (Instant Message) is logged with a Message log event.  The text of the message is included as a &lt;text&lt; parameter.</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>AdditionalAgency</value>
			<description>When an agency becomes aware that another agency may be involved, in any way, with a call, it must log an AdditionalAgency event.  The AdditionalAgency event includes an &lt;agency&gt; tag which is an Agency Identifier.  Among other uses, this event is used by PSAP management to query all logging services that may have records about a call or incident.  </description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>MergeIncident</value>
			<description>At some point in processing, an agency may determine that a call marked with an IncidentId may in fact be part of another, previously determined Incident.  When it is determined that two IncidentIds have been assigned for the same real world Incident, the Ids are merged with MergeIncident.  The MergeIncident record contains the IncidentId of the incorrectly assigned incident in the &lt;incidentId&gt; tag in the header of the log record, and the Incident Id of the actual Incident in an &lt;actualIncident&gt; tag.   Note that other agencies may not know that the Incidents are being merged, and therefore could log events against the originally assigned IncidentId.</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>ClearIncident</value>
			<description>When an agency finishes its handling of an Incident, it logs a ClearIncident record.  Other agencies may still be processing the Incident.</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>ECRFquery</value>
			<description>Any element that queries the ECRF and the ECRF itself generate an ECRFquery LogEvent.  The LogEvent includes the PIDF-LO (and only the Location Object) using the RFC4119 tags and the service URN in a &lt;service-urn&gt; tag. </description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
			<value>ECRFresponse</value>
			<description>Both the elements that query the ECRF and the ECRF generate the ECRFresponse.  The entire response is logged using the LoST tags.</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
	</records>
</registry>
