<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./registry.xsl"?>
<registry xmlns="urn:nena:xml:namespace:nrs" id="service" registrar="nena" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:nena:xml:namespace:nrs registry.xsd">
	<title>urn:nena:service:sos</title>
	<created>2011-06-14</created>
	<updated>2011-06-14</updated>
    <registry ref="../../service">urn:nena:service</registry>
    <references>
        <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
    </references>
	<registration_rule>NENA Document Required</registration_rule>
	<description>Routing of emergency calls within the ESInet is a primary function of this specification.  When ESRPs must route calls within the ESInet, they query the ECRF for the route.  Routing for emergency calls may involve multiple levels of ESRPs.  Each level may need a different urn to distinguish them (it is also possible for the ECRF to distinguish by the identity of the ESRP that queries it).   Routing of emergency calls, including instant messages and non human initiated calls, is accomplished with a urn beginning with urn:nena:service:sos.</description>
    <note>A new entry to urn:nena:service:sos requires an explanation of when the urn will be used, and how the new label is distinguished in its use from other urns.  It should describe who creates urns with the label, and who uses such urns.</note>
	<records>
		<record>
			<value>psap</value>
			<description>Route calls to primary PSAP</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
		<record>
			<value>level_2_esrp</value>
			<description>Route calls to a second level ESRP (for an example, a state ESRP routing towards a county ESRP).</description>
            <references>
                <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
            </references>
            <date>2011-06-14</date>
		</record>
        <record>
      			<value>level_3_esrp</value>
      			<description>Route calls to a third level ESRP (for example, a regional ESRP that received a call from a state ESRP and in turn routes towards a county ESRP).</description>
                  <references>
                      <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
                  </references>
                  <date>2011-06-14</date>
      		</record>
        <record>
      			<value>call_taker</value>
      			<description>Route calls to a call taker within a PSAP</description>
                  <references>
                      <xref type="nena" data="i3_Stage3">08-003 v1</xref>
                  </references>
                  <date>2011-06-14</date>
      		</record>
	</records>
</registry>
